Guide to the Felix S. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Collegial - Institutional Affiliations, 1935-1953; Series IV; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  - INSTITUTE OF LIVING LAW
    - "Handbook of Propaganda Warfare"
      - Various drafts, chapter 3, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1270-72)
      - Various drafts, chapter 4, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1273-75)
      - Various drafts, appendix A (Box 81, Folder 1276)
      - Various drafts, appendix B (Box 82, Folder 1277)
      - Correspondence, 1941-47 (Box 82, Folder 1278-81)
      - Background material, chapter 1, 1940 (Box 82, Folder 1282)
      - Background material, chapter 2, 1942, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1283-84)
      - Background material, chapter 3, 1939-42, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1285-93)
      - Background material, appendix A, 1941-42 (Box 82, Folder 1294-95)
      - Background material, appendix B, 1941 (Box 83, Folder 1296)
      - Background material, appendix C, 1942, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1297)
      - Background material, 1937-43, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1298-1309)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1629
      - Review, sale, receipts of Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Reappraisal, 1944-50 (Box 83, Folder 1310)
      - Review, sale, receipts of Combating Totalitarian Propaganda: A Legal Reappraisal, 1944-45 (Box 84, Folder 1311)
  - OTHER ORGANIZATIONS
    - American Bar Association, 1942-52 (Box 84, Folder 1312-15)
    - American Philosophical Association, 1950-53 (Box 84, Folder 1316)
    - Association of American Law Schools, 1952 (Box 84, Folder 1317)
    - Conference on Jewish Relations, 1948-53 (Box 84, Folder 1318-24)
    - Council for Democracy, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 1325-30)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1630
    - Encampment for Citizen, 1953 (Box 85, Folder 1331)
    - Freeland League, 1947 (Box 85, Folder 1332)
      See also: Box 89, folder 1426
    - National Council of Law Students, 1940-41 (Box 85, Folder 1333)
    - National Lawyers Guild: Committee on International Law, 1937-39 (Box 85, Folder 1334-35)
    - National Lawyers Guild and arms embargo, 1935-41 (Box 85, Folder 1336)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1631
    - National Lawyers Guild: correspondence re: Spanish Report, 1937-38 (Box 85, Folder 1337)
    - National Lawyers Guild: history of Spanish report, 1937-38 (Box 85, Folder 1338)
    - Yiddish Scientific Institute - Yivo, 1944-46 (Box 85, Folder 1339)
- Personal Papers, 1933-1992; Series V; 4.5; (11 boxes)
  The series is divided into Correspondence and Cohen Family Material, in which material is organized under individual's names. Correspondents with less than five letters have been placed in "Letter" general files.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1945-53 (Box 86, Folder 1340)
    - American Jewish Congress
      See: Box 88, folder 1394
    - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith
      See: Box 89, folder 1428
    - Association on American Indian Affairs
      See: Box 87, folder 1389
    - "B" general, 1946-53 (Box 86, Folder 1341)
    - Becker, Edward, 1948 (Box 86, Folder 1342)
    - Becker, William, 1948-50 (Box 86, Folder 1343)
    - Bedwell, Rita, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 1344)
    - Billikopf, Jacob, 1945-49 (Box 86, Folder 1345)
    - Blau, Joseph L., 1946-52 (Box 86, Folder 1346)
    - Bronson, Ruth, 1946-48 (Box 86, Folder 1347)
    - Bronstein, Daniel J., 1946-49 (Box 86, Folder 1348)
    - Bronston, Jack, 1947-53 (Box 86, Folder 1349)
    - Brophy, William, 1946-52 (Box 86, Folder 1350)
    - "C" general, 1944-53 (Box 86, Folder 1351)
    - Cairns, Huntington, 1946-49 (Box 86, Folder 1352)
    - Calvin, Ruth, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 1353)
    - Carus, Elizabeth, 1946-47 (Box 86, Folder 1354)
    - Chavez, Dennis, 1946-49 (Box 86, Folder 1355)
    - City College of New York
      See: Box 86, folder 1348
    - Cofrances, Humbert, 1947-49 (Box 86, Folder 1356)
    - Cohen, Elliot E., 1946-49 (Box 86, Folder 1357)
    - Cohen, Henry, 1946-50 (Box 86, Folder 1358)
    - Cohen, Victor W., 1947-53 (Box 86, Folder 1359)
    - Collier, John, 1946-48 (Box 86, Folder 1360)
    - Commentary
      See: Box 86, folder 1356
    - Conference on Jewish Relations
      See: Box 86, folder 1346
    - "D" general, 1946-53 (Box 86, Folder 1361)
    - The Day, 1946-48 (Box 86, Folder 1362)
    - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1948 Mar (Box 86, Folder 1363)
    - "E" general, 1945-52 (Box 86, Folder 1364)
    - "F" general, 1940-52 (Box 86, Folder 1365)
    - Faris, Chester, 1948-52 (Box 86, Folder 1366)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1947-51 (Box 87, Folder 1367)
    - "G" general, 1946-52 (Box 87, Folder 1368)
    - Gilbert, Willam, 1946 (Box 87, Folder 1369)
    - Green, Mrs. Lawrence, 1952 (Box 87, Folder 1370)
    - "H" general, 1942-53 (Box 87, Folder 1371)
    - Haas, Theodore H., 1947-51 (Box 87, Folder 1372)
    - Hart, John B, 1950-51 (Box 87, Folder 1373)
    - Hirsch, William, 1947-52 (Box 87, Folder 1374)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1947-49 (Box 87, Folder 1375)
    - Howard University
      See: Box 86, folder 1345
    - Howe, Mark DeWolfe, 1946-49 (Box 87, Folder 1376)
    - Hyman, Jerome, 1946-52 (Box 87, Folder 1377)
    - "I" general, 1948-53 (Box 87, Folder 1378)
    - Ickes, Harold L., 1947-51 (Box 87, Folder 1379)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1632
    - Indian Affairs Forum
      See: Box 86, folder 1347
    - International Rescue & Relief Committee
      See: Box 88, folder 1399
    - "J" general, 1946-51 (Box 87, Folder 1380)
    - Journal of the History of Ideas
      See: Box 89, folder 1434
    - "K" general, 1945-52 (Box 87, Folder 1381)
    - Kaplan, Benjamin, 1946-53 (Box 87, Folder 1382)
    - Kilpatrick, William Heard, 1949 (Box 87, Folder 1383)
    - Koenigsberger, Lawrence, 1949 (Box 87, Folder 1384)
    - Konvitz, Milton R., 1940-48 (Box 87, Folder 1385)
    - Kramer, Sidney, 1950 (Box 87, Folder 1386)
    - "L" general, 1946-53 (Box 87, Folder 1387)
    - Lachman, Karl E., 1950-52 (Box 87, Folder 1388)
    - Lesser, Alexander, 1947-48 (Box 87, Folder 1389)
    - Levine, Pearl Ann, 1951-53 (Box 88, Folder 1390)
    - Levinson, Bernard, 1948-9 (Box 88, Folder 1391)
    - Littell, Norman, 1947-49 (Box 88, Folder 1392)
    - "M" general, 1938-53 (Box 88, Folder 1393)
    - Maslow, Will, 1946-48 (Box 88, Folder 1394)
    - Mermin, Samuel, 1948-49 (Box 88, Folder 1395)
    - Merritt, Marjorie, 1946-53 (Box 88, Folder 1396)
    - Meyer, Arthur, 1948-53 (Box 88, Folder 1397)
    - Meyer, Marion (Box 88, Folder 1397)
    - Michael, Jerome, 1948-52 (Box 88, Folder 1398)
    - Mishnun, Virginia, 1944-53 (Box 88, Folder 1399)
    - Mitchell, Irene (née Williams), 1950-51 (Box 88, Folder 1400)
    - "N" general, 1947-53 (Box 88, Folder 1401)
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1946-47 (Box 88, Folder 1402)
    - National Conference of Bar Examiners
      See: Box 88, folder 1396
    - Nelson, Everett, 1948 (Box 88, Folder 1403)
    - Nichols, Lester M., 1947-48 (Box 88, Folder 1404)
    - North Dakota Indian Affairs Commission
      See: Box 87, folder 1373
    - "O" general, 1946-52 (Box 88, Folder 1405)
    - Open Court Publishing Company
      See: Box 86, folder 1354
    - Opler, Morris, 1946-53 (Box 88, Folder 1406)
    - "P" general, 1946-53 (Box 88, Folder 1407)
    - Paul, William L., 1948 (Box 88, Folder 1408)
    - Powell, Richard R., 1947-48 (Box 88, Folder 1409)
    - Providencia, Sister, 1950-52 (Box 88, Folder 1410)
    - "R" general, 1941-53 (Box 88, Folder 1411)
    - Rackman, Emanuel, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 1412)
    - Ratner, Sidney, 1947-48 (Box 88, Folder 1413)
    - Rosenfield, Harry N., 1945-53, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 1414)
      Contains material given to Lucy M. Kramer by H. N. Rosenfield
    - Rostow, Eugene, 1945-47 (Box 88, Folder 1415)
    - Roth, Louis and Jane, 1947-53 (Box 88, Folder 1416)
    - "S" general, 1946-53 (Box 89, Folder 1417)
    - Schott, Howard M., 1949-53, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1418)
    - Sheffer, Henry M., 1947, 1949 (Box 89, Folder 1419)
    - Sheinkman, Shepard A., 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1420)
    - Shientag, Bernard L., 1947-52 (Box 89, Folder 1421)
    - Shulterbrandt, Louis, 1946, 1952 (Box 89, Folder 1422)
    - Shulterbrandt, Eldra (Box 89, Folder 1422)
    - Singer, Rita, 1946-52 (Box 89, Folder 1423)
    - Speier, Leonard, 1949 (Box 89, Folder 1424)
    - Stein, Charles, 1947 (Box 89, Folder 1425)
    - Steinberg, I. N., 1945-50 (Box 89, Folder 1426)
    - "T" general, 1946-53 (Box 89, Folder 1427)
    - Trager, Frank, 1947-49 (Box 89, Folder 1428)
    - "U" general, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1429)
    - "Y" general, 1950-53 (Box 89, Folder 1430)
    - Vining, Roscoe H., 1947-48 (Box 89, Folder 1431)
    - "W" general, 1941-53 (Box 89, Folder 1432)
    - Wallach, Sidney, 1947-48 (Box 89, Folder 1433)
    - Wiener, Philip P., 1947-50 (Box 89, Folder 1434)
    - "Y" general, 1946, 1948 (Box 89, Folder 1435)
    - Young, Malcolm M., 1949 (Box 89, Folder 1436)
    - "Z" general, 1948-49 (Box 89, Folder 1437)
    - Contributions, A -L, 1950-53 (Box 89, Folder 1438)
    - Contributions, M - Z, 1950-53 (Box 90, Folder 1439)
    - Invitations, 1950-53 (Box 90, Folder 1440-44)
    - Resignation letters, 1947-48 (Box 90, Folder 1445-17)
    - Vacation correspondence, 1948-50 (Box 90, Folder 1448-50)
  - COHEN FAMILY MATERIAL
    - Felix S. Cohen and Lucy M. Kramer
      - Anti-Nazi, 1939, 1941 (Box 90, Folder 1451)
      - Awards, Honors, Memorial Services for Cohen
        - Awards, 1948-49 (Box 90, Folder 1452)
        - Department of the Interior - exhibit honoring Cohen, 1954 (Box 90, Folder 1453)
        - Eternal Light (radio program), aired "The Fig Tree," a biographical tribute to Cohen, 1953-54 (Box 91, Folder 1454-55)
        - Felix S. Cohen Memorial Fund, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 1456-62)
        - Felix S. Cohen Memorial Fund committee, presentation of Cohen portrait to CCNY, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 1463)
        - Funeral service, 1953 Oct 21, 1953-54, 1991 (Box 91, Folder 1464-65)
        - Indian Claims Commission memorial service, 1953 Dec 4, 1953-54 (Box 91, Folder 1466)
        - Publicity, 1953-89 (Box 91, Folder 1467)
          See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1653
        - Riegelman, Strasser, Schwarz & Spiegelberg press releases, 1953 (Box 91, Folder 1468)
        - Rutgers Law Review memorial issue, 1954 (Box 91, Folder 1469)
        - Testimonial dinner January 17, 1948 for Felix S. Cohen, pamphlet documenting event published by Theodore H. Haas (Box 92, Folder 1470)
      - Beybel, Rosia Fuchs - immigration case, 1945-46 (Box 92, Folder 1471)
      - Cohen biographical information, 1933-46 (Box 92, Folder 1472)
      - Cohen biographical information, 1947-54, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1473)
      - Cohen's desk and desk tray - papers, 1947-54, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1474-75)
      - Editors of 1982 Edition of Handbook presentation to Lucy M. Kramer (Box 92, Folder 1476)
      - Employment bills, 1947 (Box 92, Folder 1477)
      - Grorud, A. A., 1950-52 (Box 92, Folder 1478)
      - Holman, Nat - Publicity (newspaper), 1952 (Box 92, Folder 1479)
      - Holman, Nat - CCNY, 1950-53 (Box 92, Folder 1480)
      - Immigration affidavits, 1941-41, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1481)
      - Immigration, etc., 1938-40 (Box 93, Folder 1482)
      - "Indian Self-Rule: Fifty Years Under the Indian Reorganization Act," conference program, Charolette L. Westwood and Lucy M. Kramer were participants, 1983 Aug (Box 93, Folder 1483)
      - Insurance policies and bonds, 1943-53 (Box 93, Folder 1484)
      - Kramer's biographical information, 1946 (Box 93, Folder 1485)
      - Kramer's Correspondence
        - "A-C" general, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1486)
        - Association on American Indian Affairs, 1952-54 (Box 93, Folder 1487)
        - "D-J" general, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1488)
        - District of Columbia Inheritance and Estate Tax Division, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1489)
        - "K-M" general, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1490)
        - "N-R" general, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1491)
        - "S-Z" general, 1954 (Box 93, Folder 1492)
        - Miscellaneous, [1954] (Box 93, Folder 1493)
      - Kramer's letters to Cohen, 1945 (Box 93, Folder 1494)
      - Kramer's letters to the archivist, 1990-92 (Box 93, Folder 1495)
      - Kramer's work for Riegelman, Strasser, Schwarz & Spiegelberg, 1954, 1985 (Box 93, Folder 1496-98)
      - Margold, Judge Nathan Ross, 1935-48 (Box 93, Folder 1499)
      - Margold Judgeship, 1935-45, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 1500-02)
      - Pearson, Drew - controversy, 1952 (Box 94, Folder 1503)
      - Photographs, ca. 1950 (Box 94, Folder 1504-06)
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1507-08)
      - Publications collected by Cohen, 1942-53, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1509)
      - Refugee Problems, 1939-41 (Box 94, Folder 1510)
      - Refugees, 1940-41 (Box 94, Folder 1511)
      - Russell, Bertrand - case, 1940-41 (Box 94, Folder 1512-15)
      - Safety deposit box, 1954-51 (Box 94, Folder 1516)
      - Selective service - draft deferment for Cohen, 1940-45 (Box 94, Folder 1517)
      - Social security benefits re: Yale employment, 1953-54 (Box 94, Folder 1518)
      - Supporting loyalty affidavits by Cohen for individuals accused of being un-American, 1948-54, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 1519)
      - "A Symposium on Indian Law," Oregon Law Review (sent to Lucy M. Kramer by Arthur Lazarus, Jr.), 1983, 1989 (Box 94, Folder 1520)
      - Taxes, 1948-50 (Box 95, Folder 1521-23)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1633
      - Taxes, 1945-52 (Box 95, Folder 1524-31)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-53 (Box 95, Folder 1532)
    - Morris R. Cohen
      See also: Box 74, folder 1175
      - Unpublished material summary, 1954 Apr (Box 95, Folder 1533)
      - American Thought: correspondence, 1954-55 (Box 95, Folder 1534-35)
      - American Thought: correspondence, 1954-55 (Box 95, Folder 1536-37)
      - American Thought: notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1538-39)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1654
      - American Thought: reviews, 1954-55 (Box 96, Folder 1540-42)
      - A Dreamer's Journey: correspondence (Box 96, Folder 1543)
      - Law and Social Order: permission's correspondence, 1953-54 (Box 96, Folder 1544)
      - Correspondence, 1945-49 (Box 96, Folder 1545)
      - Obituary, 1947 Jan 30 (Box 96, Folder 1546)
    - Leonora C. and Harry N. Rosenfield
      - Family correspondence, 1940-57, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 1547)
      - Letters of sympathy received on Felix S. Cohen's death, 1953 (Box 96, Folder 1548-52)
      - Biographical material on Felix S. Cohen, 1948-61 (Box 96, Folder 1553)
      - Biographical material on Harry N. Rosenfield collected by Felix S. Cohen, 1951-52 (Box 96, Folder 1554)
      - Articles about Morris R. Cohen by Leonora C. and Harry N. Rosenfield, 1981 (Box 96, Folder 1555)
- Arthur Lazarus Addition, 1928-54; Series VI; 1; (3 boxes)
  The papers in Series VI are Felix S. Cohen's files, created when he worked for the Interior Department, released and brought by him into private practice. The original folder titles have been preserved, any alterations or additions appear in brackets []. The files have been alphabetically arranged under Indian Constitutions and Other Material.
  - INDIAN CONSTITUTIONS
    - California constitutions, 1935-36 (Box 97, Folder 1556)
    - Cheyenne River Sioux [constitution], 1935 (Box 97, Folder 1557)
    - Chippewa bands of Wis. and Mich. [constitutions], 1935-36 (Box 97, Folder 1558)
    - Colorado River [Indian constitution], 1935-45 (Box 97, Folder 1559)
    - Eastern Cherokee [Indian constitution], 1934-35 (Box 97, Folder 1560)
    - Fort Belknap [constitution], 1933-45, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1561-63)
    - Constitution, bylaws [Fort Belknap], 1933-36 (Box 97, Folder 1564)
    - Hopi [Indian constitution], 1936 Aug 28 (Box 97, Folder 1565)
    - Menominee [tribal charter], 1936 (Box 97, Folder 1566)
    - Mescalero Apache [constitution], 1936 (Box 97, Folder 1567)
    - Navajo constitution, 1928-48 (Box 97, Folder 1568)
    - [Navajo tribal constitution], 1928-46, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 1569-71)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1634
    - Papago [Indian constitution], 1936 (Box 98, Folder 1572)
    - Siouan Indians of North Carolina [constitution], 1935-38 (Box 98, Folder 1573)
    - Ute and So[uth] Ute constitutions, 1935-36 (Box 98, Folder 1574)
    - Washington Oregon Tribes [constitution], 1935-36 (Box 98, Folder 1575)
    - Western Shosone [of Nevada constitution], 1934-36 (Box 98, Folder 1576-79)
    - Wisconsin Oneidas [constitution], 1935 (Box 98, Folder 1580)
    - Yuma [Quechan Tribe constitution], 1934-35 (Box 98, Folder 1581-82)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Boulder city, 1939-40 (Box 98, Folder 1583)
    - Hearings...on...HR 4453...to Prohibit Discrimination in employment because of race, color, religion, or national origin, 1949 (Box 98, Folder 1584)
    - Indian Delegation Act [right of Secretary of the Interior to delegate power to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs], 1942-46 (Box 98, Folder 1585)
    - Indian office - Navajo trespass, 1935-48 (Box 98, Folder 1586-87)
    - Isleta Pueblo - (Jiron, etc), 1934-43, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 1588-91)
    - Klamath enrollment bill, 1935, n.d. (Box 99, Folder 1592)
    - Labor's Non-Partisan League
      - National Bulletin, 1937-39 (Box 99, Folder 1593-94)
      - Supreme Court Calendar, 1937 (Box 99, Folder 1595)
      - Publications, 1937 (Box 99, Folder 1596)
    - Miscellaneous Indian bills (House Indian committee), 1945-46 (Box 99, Folder 1597)
    - Newspaper articles on sale of Indian land intertribal policy, 1954 Feb 9 (Box 99, Folder 1598)
    - US Constitution, etc. [address by Harold L. Ickes], 1937 (Box 99, Folder 1599)
    - Ute [land claims], 1943 (Box 99, Folder 1600)
    - Water rights litigation, 1935 (Box 99, Folder 1601)
- Oversize, 4; (3 boxes) + 7 broadside folders
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series I, III, IV, and V. The arrangement is based on the size of the material, but it also parallels the order of the collection.
  - SERIES I. LEGAL CAREER
    - Indian Affairs
      - Department of the Interior. Commission to the Five Civilized Tribes. Map Showing Progress of Allotment in Cherokee Nation, 1904 (Box BSD, folder 1602)
      - Mexico [Northern American Indian policy], 1938 (Box BSD, folder 1603)
    - Indian Law Survey
      - Miscellaneous material, 1935, n.d. (Box BSD, folder 1604)
    - Alaska: Natural Resources and Native Affairs
      - Karluk - Litigation, 1947 (Box BSD, folder 1605)
    - Territories
      - "Inventory of United States Land Resources and their Use - 1500-1950," chart, 1946 (Box BSD, folder 1606)
    - Solicitor's Office Records
      - Atomic energy, ca. 1945-46 (Box BSD, folder 1607)
      - Office organization, n.d. (Box BSD, folder 1608)
    - Indian Affairs
      - Indians on a New Trail - Misc (Box 100, Folder 1609)
    - Indian Law Survey
      - Page proofs, 1940 edition published by Government Printing Office, ca. 1940 (Box 100, Folder 1610-14)
      - Draft Outline of Indian Law (Box 100, Folder 1615)
      - Analytical Index of Federal Indian Law (Box 100, Folder 1616)
    - Alaska: Natural Resources and Native Affairs
      - Alaska - Publicity, 1946 Mar 31 (Box 100, Folder 1617)
      - Alaska - 1945, 1944-46 (Box 100, Folder 1618)
      - Alaska Native Brotherhood, 1943 Nov 29 (Box 100, Folder 1619)
      - Alaska General - "Cohen Raps Alaska Colonialism: Government, Industry Both Blamed," Alaska Federationist v. 3, no. 15 (Juneau, Alaska), 1948 May (Box 100, Folder 1620)
      - Alaska Reservations - General, 1950 Jul 30 (Box 100, Folder 1621)
    - Territories
      - PR 1934 on, 1949-50 (Box 100, Folder 1622)
      - Virgin Islands ["The First Negro Governor," Saturday Evening Post ], 1948 Apr 17 (Box 100, Folder 1623)
    - Private Practice
      - Migratory agriculture labor legislation, 1950 (Box 100, Folder 1624)
  - SERIES II. TEACHING CAREER
    - Yale Courses
      - Legislative drafting seminar - correspondence, 1946 (Box 100, Folder 1625)
  - SERIES III. WRITING PROJECTS
    - Addresses
      - "Democracy and the War", 1950, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1626)
      - "The Relationship between Ethics and Law", 1949 (Box 100, Folder 1627)
  - SERIES IV. COLLEGIAL - INSTITUTIONAL AFFILIATIONS
    - Institute of Living Law
      - Pacific Charter and colonialism, 1942 (Box 100, Folder 1628)
      - "Handbook of Propaganda Warfare:" Background material, 1940, 1942, n.d. (Box 100, Folder 1629)
    - Other Institutions
      - Council for Democracy, 1941-42 (Box 100, Folder 1630)
      - National Lawyers Guild and arms embargo, 1937 Dec (Box 100, Folder 1631)
  - SERIES V. PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Correspondence
      - Ickes, Harold L., 1948 Jun 12 (Box 100, Folder 1632)
      - Taxes, 1948-50 (Box 100, Folder 1633)
  - SERIES VI. ARTHUR LAZARUS ADDITION
    - Indian Constitutions
      - [Navajo tribal constitution], 1939 Apr 1 (Box 100, Folder 1634)
  - SERIES I. LEGAL CAREER
    - Indian Affairs
      - Tribal Organization - Legal Data, 1936 (Box 101, Folder 1635)
    - Alaska: Natural Resources and Native Affairs
      - Alaskan - Publicity: Kethcikan Alaska Chronicle, 1944 Oct 24 (Box 101, Folder 1636)
      - Alaska bill publicity, 1942 (Box 101, Folder 1637)
      - Alaska Development Program: 1946, "What's Wrong with Alaska?, The Washington Post, 1946 Aug 18 (Box 101, Folder 1638)
    - Territories - Puerto Rico
      - Agricultural Company Case, Suarez- Martinez v. Tugwell: Clippings, 1946 (Box 101, Folder 1639)
      - Parks and Conservation, 1933-36 (Box 101, Folder 1640)
      - Budget survey [recommendations for structure of legal work in Interior Dept.] (Box 101, Folder 1641)
      - Official Status - Felix S. Cohen Department of Interior, 1941 (Box 101, Folder 1642)
    - Private Practice Office Records
      - Time sheets, 1949-51 (Box 101, Folder 1643-45)
      - Time records, 1948-49 (Box 101, Folder 1646)
      - Time records - monthly totals, 1948-52 (Box 101, Folder 1647)
      - Time records - monthly (FSC), 1952 (Box 101, Folder 1648)
      - Time records - monthly, 1953 (Box 101, Folder 1649)
  - SERIES III. WRITING PROJECTS
    - Addresses
      - "American's Minorities - The Administrative Record", 1944 Oct 21 (Box 101, Folder 1650)
      - "Ethics of Our Foreign Policy," University of Texas Great Issues Class, 1951 Dec 6 (Box 101, Folder 1651)
    - Works by Others
      - "Noble Red Man - American Indians Are Tired of Being Treated Like Irresponsible Children," by Fred Theroux, 1952 Jul 20 (Box 101, Folder 1652)
  - SERIES V. PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Cohen Family Material - Felix S. Cohen and Lucy M. Kramer
      - Publicity, 1953 (Box 101, Folder 1653)
    - Cohen Family Material - Morris R. Cohen
      - American Thought: notes, 1948 Sep 22 (Box 101, Folder 1654)
- Restricted Papers, 1; (3 boxes)
  The material taken from Series VII is restricted until 2025. The dictaphone records taken from Series V are restricted until a preservation recording can be made.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until 2025. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Restricted papers (Box 102, Folder 1655-72)
  - Restricted papers (Box 103, Folder 1673-82)
  - Restricted papers (Box 104, Folder 1683-93)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Restricted Fragile Papers, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order.
  - Box 92, folder 1474-1475 (Box 105, Folder 1694-95)